一切准备就绪
All set.
谢谢
Thanks.
(献血)
你看的这篇是什么
What do you got there?
抱歉 你读的是什么
Sorry. What do you got there?
托尔斯泰的《伊凡伊里奇之死》中 宗教皈依主题
Themes of religious conversion in Tolstoy's The Death of Ivan Ilyich.
天啊 剧透了
Oh, my God. Spoiler alert, please.
你呢
What about you?
- 你在看... - 我 这是...
- Are you reading... - Me? Well... It's...
噢 对 这篇特别精彩
Oh, yeah, this is a real treat.
“西线无瘾士
"All Quiet on the Western Blunt:
一战士兵的毒品使用”
Drug Use by Enlisted Soldiers during World War I."
- 不 别逗了 - 不 真的是写的这个
- No, stop. - No, that's what it is.
这孩子是个天才 你应该让其他人都不及格
Kid's a genius. You should flunk every other child.
完全同意
I couldn't agree more.
不好意思 你是
I'm sorry. Who are you?
珍玛
Gemma.
好的
All right.
马克
Mark.
- 很高兴认识你 马克 - 彼此彼此
- Nice to meet you, Mark. - You too.
珍玛 你神游到哪去了
Gemma, where did you go?
他不会有事的
He'll be okay.
可能会有些神经功能缺失
There might be some deficits.
但希望不会有任何长期后遗症
Hopefully, nothing long term.
你是医生吗
Are you a doctor?
我们需要叫救护车吗
Do we need an ambulance?
你能不能回答一下问题 拜托了
Can you answer one of my questions, please?
- 我们需要叫救护车吗  - 不用
- Do we need an ambulance? - No.
他会睡一段时间
He's gonna sleep for a while.
好吧 多久
Okay. How long?
很难说
Hard to say.
我们需要楼下的一些设备 你手脚灵活吗
We'll need some equipment from downstairs. Are you clumsy?
什么 为什么 你的设备会在马克的地下室
What? Why do you have equipment in Mark's basement?
你哥哥正在恢复记忆
Your brother's reintegrating.
他才没有
No, he's not.
- 我知道这令人感到不安 - 好吧
- I know that was troubling. - Okay.
我能看出来 你比我聪明
I can tell that you're smarter than me,
所以我这么直白地说你别介意
so forgive me if I say this, like, super plainly,
如果你哪怕有一丝一毫的念头 要再去搞我哥哥
but if you give one solitary thought to messing with my brother again,
我会把你从桥上扔下去
I will throw you off a fucking bridge.
- 德文 - 我们不要再经历那个了
- Devon-- - We don't do that again.
- 我们之后再详谈 - 不
- We'll discuss it later. - Nope!
不 这位小姐 现在就敲定 不再改了 懂吗
No. It's settled fucking law, lady, okay?
你就接受吧
Just accept it.
一切到此为止
The end.
这是他想要的
It's what he wants.
他想要的是查清珍玛是不是还活着
What he wants is to know whether Gemma's alive or not.
她还活着
She is.
请别和我扯大话
Please don't mess with me.
她还活着
She is alive.
人生切割术
第二季 第七集
(摄氏36.4度)
亲 你今天吃过了吗
You've eaten today, honey?
吃了
Yes.
读完了
Done your reading?
50页
Fifty pages.
健身操
Calisthenics?
做了
Yes.
(强度 悲哀 右)
如果你在泥石流期间被困
If you were caught in a mudslide,
你更担心窒息而亡还是溺亡
would you be more afraid of suffocating or drowning?
溺亡
Drowning.
(强度 悲哀 左)
今天多少个房间
How many rooms today?
六个
Six.
该死
Shit.
(阿伦敦)
(凯恩斯市)
(德兰斯维尔)
(西纳)
(拉夫兰)
(威灵顿)
准备好了
Ready?
来了呀
There she is.
我能休息一下吗
Could I please get a break?
只是一小会儿
Just for a little while.
但已经过了六周了
But it's been six weeks.
我刚才来过这里
I was just here.
我知道
I know.
大家都不喜欢看牙医
Nobody likes the dentist.
我应该听我妈的话当个会计的
I should have been an accountant like my mom wanted.
请坐
Please, have a seat.
非常好
Excellent.
好 我们来看看你的情况
Now, let's see how we're doing.
请张大嘴
Open wide, please.
我在里面待了多久
How long was I in there?
两个小时
Two hours.
(冷港)
好的
Okay.
噢 哥啊
Oh, bud.
太太 醒过来吧
I need you back, m'lady.
请醒过来
Please come back.
- 嗨 噢 长命百岁 - 嗨
- Hey. Oh, bless you. - Hey.
不好意思
Excuse me.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hey.
昨晚很开心
That was fun last night.
我也是
It was.
抱歉 我3点有一堂 关于《哈吉穆拉德》的课
I'm sorry. I have a lecture at 3:00 on Hadji Murad
- 我的笔记乱透了 - 不...没关系
- and my notes are all over the place. - No. That's... It's okay.
我就是...给你带了个东西
I just... I brought you something.
蚂蚁农庄
It's an ant farm.
昨晚你说你喜欢蚂蚁 所以...
Last night you said you liked ants. So...
我说我喜欢...植物
I said I liked... I like plants.
植物
Plants.
- 我讨厌蚂蚁 - 噢 糟糕
- I hate ants. - Oh, shit.
- 可是我...很喜欢农庄 - 那就好
- But I... I love farms. - Good.
我还差好多
I'm so fucking behind.
就当我不在
I'm not even here.
你不在 好的
You're not here? Okay.
你在做什么
What are you doing? What are you doing?
对
Yeah.
- 真的  - 你知道 它在减价
- Really? - Well, I mean, you know, it was on sale.
那么 谁来组装 你这位工匠大师吗
And who's putting it together, Mr. Handyman? You?
其实我挺擅长做手工活的
I happen to be quite handy.
你才不是
No, you're not.
- 什么 怎么可以这么说 - 是毛手毛脚
- What? How dare you. - Handsy.
毛手毛脚
Handsy?
好吧 可能我是挺毛手毛脚的
All right. Maybe I am kinda handsy.
- 是吗  - 我喜欢
- Yeah? - I like it.
是 这...
Yeah. Well...
我就希望提到这个
This is what I was hoping would come up.
发生了什么
What happened?
其实真的没那么糟
It really, truly wasn't that bad.
对你来说是 因为你能像壁虎一样爬墙
For you. That's 'cause you can scale walls like a gecko.
这...有800米都是裸岩
This... It was like half a mile of just exposed rock face.
- 岩石 对 - 听起来很有趣
- Boulders. Fine. - It sounds fun.
是有几块岩石
There were a few boulders.
岩石 宝贝 拜托 那看起来就像珠穆朗玛峰的死亡区
Boulders? Babe, come on. It was like the death zone of Everest.
就像珠峰
Like Chomolungma.
- 有冻死的尸骨吗  - 没有 我专门看过
- Any frozen bodies? - No, I looked.
但我有照片证据 你看看
But I do have photo evidence. Look at them.
- 天啊 你有什么毛病  - 看
- Oh, my God. What's wrong with you? - Look.
- 对啊 里肯 你有什么毛病  - 是吧
- Yeah, Ricken, what is wrong with you? - Yeah.
嘿 我第一次系上攀岩带是中学时
Hey, I belayed my first couloir in middle school.
- 我... - 什么
- So, I... - What?
什么
What?
- 听起来很痛 - 我们都知道那什么意思
- That sounds painful. - We all know what that means.
真抱歉你们被迫听
I'm sorry he said that.
我体内流淌着户外探险的血
Outdoorsmanship courses through my veins.
- 我觉得很性感 - 我不道歉
- I think it's hot. - I make no apology for it.
等等 要怎么下去呢
Wait, how did you get down?
- 我是屁股蹭着慢慢下去 - 有照片吗
- I scooted on my ass. - Are there photos of that?
没 那是禁止拍照区
No. It was a no-photo zone.
禁止拍照的死亡区
A no-photo death zone.
没错 谢谢
Exactly. Thank you.
你我以后会一起探险 我们俩
You and I will ramble together someday. The two of us.
一场大冒险
It will be a grand adventure.
我觉得我们总是待在一起
I feel like we spend a lot of time together.
- 远远不够 马克 - 真的
- Not enough. No, Mark. - Really?
- 你不喝点吗  - 我们要做什么
- Are you not drinking? - What are we gonna do there?
你知道其实可以从尿液提炼...
Did you know you can purify urine into...
- 逗我呢 - ...可饮用水
- Oh, fuck right off. - ...drinkable water?
为什么要做那种事
Why would I do that?
为了体验自然的美丽与奇妙
To experience the beauty and wonder of nature.
但你为什么这么渴望做这件事
But why is it you want to do this so bad?
- 好 - 我想增进对你的了解
- Okay. - I want to know you better.
你为什么非要我跟你一起...
Why is it you need to have me come with you...
嘿 亲爱的 你知道我把钥匙放哪儿了吗
Hey, hon. Do you know where I put the keys?
- 你还好吗 噢 宝贝 - 不
- Are you okay? Oh, baby. - No.
凯西女士
Ms. Casey.
我是来这里观察赫莉R的
I'm here to observe Helly R.
没人告诉我啊
No one told me.
这是科贝尔女士的命令 我要观察她是否有悲伤的迹象
Ms. Cobel's orders. I am to watch her for signs of sadness,
并用语言鼓励她放弃未来自杀的念头
and verbally encourage her to forgo further suicide attempts.
(德兰斯维尔 卢蒙)
(冷港)
记忆分离屏障还有效吗
Are the severance barriers holding?
是的 该技术有效
Yes, the technology is working.
你喜欢她
You like her.
她很讨人喜欢
She's easy to like.
当然 她也喜欢我
She is fond of me too, of course.
她不是曾试图弄断你的手指吗
Didn't she try and break your fingers?
嗨 请稍等
Hi. I'll be right with you.
谢谢
Thanks.
你知道...
You know...
对很多人来说 这是下一个选择
it's the next step for a lot of people.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
对不起
I'm sorry.
(新病人登记表)
(联络信息 名字:珍玛)
准备好了吗
You ready?
时间到了
It's time.
准备就绪
Locked and loaded.
第三次一定行
Third time's the charm.
大家都这么说
That's what they say.
我会给你写感谢信的
I'll write you a thank-you note.
你最讨厌写感谢信了
You hate writing thank-you notes.
天 我有点紧张
Oh, my God. I'm a little nervous.
宝贝
Baby?
我说我有点紧张
I said I'm a little nervous.
噢 是 你知道
Oh, yeah. Well, you know,
这是最后一步 而且
it's the final step and, you know,
这世界上有个孩子正等着我们呢
there's a kid that's out there just waiting for us.
只要伸出手 抱住她 对吗
Just got to reach out and grab her. Right?
如果没成功呢
What if it doesn't work?
转过身 弯下腰
Turn around and bend over.
抱歉 还好吗
Sorry. You okay?
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我的嘴很疼
My mouth hurts.
哪个房间导致你的嘴疼
Which room caused your mouth to hurt?
第一个
The first one.
威灵顿
Wellington.
你今天进了多少个房间
How many rooms did you visit today?
六个
Six.
比林斯房 勒克瑙房
The Billings room, the Lucknow room,
圣皮埃尔房 凯恩斯房 苏黎世房 还有
St. Pierre, Cairns, Zurich, and...
威灵顿房 很好
The Wellington room. The Wellington. Excellent.
在房间里发生了什么  你什么都不记得吗
And what happened in the rooms? You remember nothing?
什么都不记得
Nothing.
你在走廊里有什么感觉
How did you feel in the hall?
你在走出任何房间的时候有感觉绝望吗
Did you exit any of the rooms feeling despair?
狂喜 欢乐
Fervor? Gaiety?
只剩下一个房间是我没去过的
There's only one room I haven't been to yet,
今天上面有一个名字
and today it had a name on it.
冷港
Cold Harbor.
等我去了所有房间后会发生什么
So, what happens, once I've been in all the rooms?
你会再次看见世界 世界也将看见你
You will see the world again, and the world will see you.
所以我会看见马克
So, I'll see Mark?
你所创造的世界将给马克带来福祉
Mark will benefit from the world you're siring.
基尔将带走他的所有痛苦 正如基尔带走了你的痛苦一样
Kier will take away all his pain, just as Kier has taken away yours.
你能不能说话正常一点
Can you please just talk like a normal person?
晚安 珍玛 做个好梦
Good night, Gemma. Dream sweet.
珍玛 咖啡好了
Gemma, coffee's ready!
他还好吗
Is he okay?
他情况稳定
He's stable.
那是个独立的事件
It was an isolated event.
他正在旅程途中
He's journeying now.
他什么时候会醒来
When will he wake up?
他准备好的时候
When he's ready to.
可真好
Great.
你真觉得这样会有用
You really think this is gonna work?
没有别的办法
There's no other choice.
有一个公司里的自己小屋
There's an innie cabin.
什么
Come again?
有一个...严格说来...
There... I mean, it's technically...
是一个小木屋 分离员工在那里成为公司里的自己
It's a cottage where severed people become their innies,
有一个女人...
and there was this woman--
达蒙娜产妇疗养中心
Damona Birthing Retreat.
所以 我们可以去小屋 和他公司里的自己聊聊 他可以...
Well, so maybe if we go to the cabin, we could talk to his innie, and he could--
这是完全不同的两件事
They're two completely different things.
只有这样才能救珍玛出来
This is how you get Gemma out.
你说真的吗 因为感觉 你这是要杀死我哥哥
Really, this? Because this looks like how you kill my brother.
你们俩绝对是亲兄妹
You two are definitely related.
- 我可以打给她 - 谁
- I could call her. - Who?
- 哈蒙妮科贝尔 - 什么 为什么要打给她
- Harmony Cobel. - What? Why would you do that?
她是分离层主管
She runs the severed floor.
现在不是了 她可能知道怎么进去小屋
Not anymore, she doesn't. She might know how to get in the cabin.
该死的 她甚至可能知道怎么找到珍玛
And, fuck, she might know how to get to Gemma.
她对卢蒙忠心无二
She's Lumon through and through.
她是他们一手栽培的 她是卢蒙的士兵
She was raised by them. She's a soldier.
- 这么做有风险 我懂的 - 风险
- It's a risk. I get that. - A risk?
- 对 - 她一定会告发你
- Yeah. - She will turn you over to them.
告发我们俩
Both of us.
我为了抗争而做的一切都会付之东流
Everything I've done to fight, gone.
他一醒来我们就继续治疗
We resume the treatment as soon as he wakes up.
好的 现在他的脑子归我管 不归你管了
Okay. I have custody of his brain now. You don't.
我要打给她
I'm calling her.
- 那恕我不能参与了 - 什么
- Well, then, I can't be a part of this. - What?
如果你这么做...如果你决定做这个选择...
If you do that... If you make that choice...
你...不 说真的 你在做什么
What are you... No, seriously, what are you doing?
- 祝好运 - 你不能就这样抛下他
- Good luck. - You can't leave him like this.
不...没有你 我做不到
No, no, no, I can't do this without you.
你...在闹我吗
You... Are you kidding?
你真要离开
You're leaving now?
这...不是我的选择 是你的
This... This isn't my choice. It's yours.
不 我需要你留下 我无法...
No, I need you to stay. I can't...
我不知道该怎么办 如果他醒来 我该做什么
I don't know what to do with this. What do I do if he wakes up?
别打给那个女人
Do not call that woman.
天啊
Oh, my God.
嘿
Hey.
临...
Chi...
- 马克  - 临终...
- Mark? - Chikha... Chikha...
- 你想说什么  - 临终...
- What are you trying to say? - Chikhai...
临...
Chik...
临终中阴
Chikhai bardo?
不知道 看起来像两个人在打架
I don't know. It looks like two guys fighting.
不 是同一个人 他的自我挣扎 击败自己的精神 自我之死
No, it's the same guy fighting himself, defeating his own psyche. Ego death.
你怎么知道是同一个人
How do you know it's the same guy?
头发是一样的
Well, the hair's the same.
这玩意是邮寄来的
That thing came in the mail?
对 是那种让你画只鸭子
Yeah. It's one of those things where you have to draw a duck
或兔子什么的问题
or a rabbit or whatever.
我觉得我上了诊所的邮寄名单
I think I got onto the mailing list at the clinic.
你为什么要浪费时间填它
Why are you wasting your time with this?
你为什么这么混账
Why are you being an asshole?
我没有 我只是...不知道 那感觉有点...
I'm not. I'm just... I don't know. It seems kind of...
- 奇怪 - 我填得挺开心
- weird. - I'm enjoying this.
或者说本来挺开心 直到被你毁了兴致
Or was, until you ruined it.
我觉得你有点小题大做了 珍玛
I think you might be overreacting a little bit, Gemma.
别这样
Don't do that.
怎样
Do what?
- 代我说自己的感觉 - 我不知道你是什么感觉
- Tell me how I'm feeling. - I have no idea how you're feeling.
感觉跌到谷底 被推到谷底
Like shit. Beat to shit.
那我们停一停吧
So let's stop.
别担心 这很正常
It's okay. This is perfectly normal.
我帮你把餐点准备好 用餐愉快
Let's get you set up with that meal. Bon appétit.
还需要什么吗 咖啡 茶
Can I get you anything else? Coffee? Tea?
再来一个枕头...
Another pillow...
(冷港 96%)
他卡在96%了
He's stuck at 96%.
流鼻血导致进度拖延了
The nose bleeds set us back.
他完成后 你必须和她道别
When he's done, you're gonna have to say goodbye to her.
我明白
I'm aware.
为了基尔
For Kier.
你干吗穿这件丑毛衣
Why are you wearing that stupid sweater?
亲爱的提斯戴尔先生
Dear Mr. Tisdale,
非常感谢你
I cannot thank you enough...
今年你赠送了我和我的丈夫
for the thoughtful Christmas gift
如此贴心的圣诞礼物
you sent my husband and I this year.
我们从没拥有过
We have never owned
电动灌浆机
an electric grouter.
我们非常期待
And we look forward
它将为我们带来的
to the many happy
许许多多
memories
快乐的
it will
回忆
provide.
加油 亲爱的 这是最后一封
Come on now, sweetheart. It's the last one.
没有什么...
Nothing...
比灌浆...
says...
更有...
Christmas like...
圣诞的感觉了
grouting.
其实是台除浆机
It's actually a de-grouter,
不过已经很接近了
but close enough.
我还要做多久
How much longer do I have to do this?
我说了 你已经完成任务了
I told you, you're done.
但圣诞节有趣的一点就是每年都会来
But Christmas has a funny way of coming back around each year.
天天都是圣诞节
It's always Christmas.
走吧
Let's go.
我爱你
I love you.
我刚说“我爱你”
I said, "I love you."
我也爱你
I love you too.
(塔姆沃特)
你好 珍玛
Hello, Gemma.
毛厄医生
Dr. Mauer.
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
我的手疼
My hand hurts.
是哪个房间导致你的手疼
And what room caused your hand to hurt?
阿伦敦房
Allentown.
我想回家
I want to go home.
你的丈夫去年再婚了
Your husband remarried last year...
他现在有一个女儿
and he has a daughter now.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
你离开了很久了 珍玛
You've been gone a long time, Gemma.
他已经放下过去了
He's moved on.
也许你也已经放下过去了
Maybe you've moved on too.
在其中一个房间里 你觉得呢
In one of the rooms. What do you think?
你感觉自己特别喜欢某一个房间吗
Do you feel yourself gravitating towards one room or another?
也许你在房间里拥有了 与马克在一起时从未体验过的感受
Maybe you felt things behind those doors you never felt with Mark.
也许我见到了
Maybe I've seen it.
《伊凡伊里奇之死》
The Death of Ivan Ilyich.
我猜猜结局啊 他死了
Let me guess. He dies at the end.
珍玛
Gemma!
珍玛 停下
Gemma! Stop!
珍玛
Gemma!
嘿
Hey.
你确定不一起去吗
You sure you don't want to come?
- 就是打哑谜游戏 - 那就只是玩20分钟而已
- It's charades. - That's gonna be, like, 20 minutes of it.
是 但是 你懂的
Yeah. But, you know.
要不 我也不去了
Or I could stay?
不 你最好还是去吧
No, you should probably go.
我今晚也得把这份提交了 所以...
I mean, this thing's gotta be in tonight anyway, so...
好的 你收到我发的 关于迪纳利山的资料了吗
Okay. Did you get the Denali thing I sent?
那个...没有
The... No.
我会看看的 我之后会看
I'll look at it. I'll check it out.
好 我大概10点回来
All right. Well, I'll be back at, like, 10:00.
好
Okay.
我爱你
I love you.
- 我说... - 噢 我也爱你 亲爱的 抱歉
- I said-- - Oh, no, I love you too, hon. I'm sorry.
- 拜拜 - 一会儿见
- Bye. - See you.
凯西女士
Ms. Casey.
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
发生了什么
What's happening?
没什么
Nothing.
你外面的自己进来参观公开艺术展
Your outie came in for a public art exhibition
但走错了电梯
and found herself in the wrong elevator.
我在这里多久...
How long have I been--
麻烦你转身 回去吧
If you wouldn't mind turning around and heading back in,
非常感谢
it would be greatly appreciated.
- 但... - 请
- But-- - On you go.
- 哪... - 谢谢你 凯西女士
- Where's-- - Thank you, Ms. Casey.
不...
No.
马克
Mark.
- 来吧 - 马克
- Come on. - Mark.
马克
Mark?
嘿...
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
嗨
Hi.
嘿
Hey.
小心 慢慢地
Careful. Easy.
噢 马克
Oh, Mark.
你神游到哪去了
Where'd you go?